Nethra C Tilagar

Engineer









Java Backend Developer with 1 year of experience in development. Knowing the business requirement directly from the business team, worked on development of modules along with Unit Testing, deployment of module on Server(VXML instance) and its maintenance. Looking for a Java Developer role with challenging career which encourage being creative and innovative, to effectively implement and enrich skills so as to attain a leadership position and contribute effectively to the growth of the organization, eager to learn and work in a competitive field for the betterment of both career and growth of organization.

Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals.



Skills

- PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE Java
- LIBRARIES PROFICIENT REST API
- IDE Eclipse
- TOOLS Cisco Unified call studio Postman
- Web Designing Language: HTML, CSS, Java Script ,React Native
- OPERATING SYSTEM Windows
- OTHER SKILLS Debugging, Enthusiast Learner, Team Player, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking
- Enthusiastic Learner and easily adaptable in new environment.
- Good leadership qualities.
- Accepting Challenges as Opportunity.
- Creative problem solving and good analytical skills.



Work History

2023-02 - Current

IVR Developer

Servion Global Solution, Chennai

- Analyzing, coding and implementing several modules of CVP/Java application
- Played major role in developing several applications for 14 countries in Airtel Africa

Validating Java code as well as CVP applications developed by Peers

- Mentoring team members on complex code logics and Java features like Lamda expression, anonymous classes, etc
- Providing extensive support during SIT, UAT, Go-live and Post-Production.

2022-07 - 2023-02

Trainee

Bahwan CyberTek, Karnataka

- Attended training courses to build understanding of processes, techniques, and industry.
- Learned new materials, processes, and programs quickly.
- Filled out timesheets and paperwork according to identified requirements.
- Established lasting relationships with peers, leadership and customers using strong communication and interpersonal skills.
- Shadowed senior team members to learn all related jobs and tasks.



Education

2017-03 - 2020-03

BCA – Bachelor of Computer Application

National Degree College - Karnataka

GPA: 7.9

SSLC

2015-02 - 2017-02

2002-02 - 2015-03

PCMB

Bunts Sanga RNS Vidyanikethan Composite PU College - Karnataka GPA: 71

St.Philomenas Memorial High School - Karnataka GPA: 86.8



Certifications

- Java online course
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals Microsoft Certified
- Azure Fundamentals
- Certificate on CLOUD COMPUTING